Copelof, Maxwell Arbitration Briefs, Exhibits, Transcripts and Decisions 5129
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Maxwell Copelof Arbitration Briefs Exhibits, Transcripts and Decisions
1938-1993
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Copelof, Maxwell
5129
9 cubic feet
9 linear ft.
Case files, decisions, transcripts.
Contains transcripts, briefs, awards, and decisions relating to cases arbitrated by Maxwell Copelof.
3833937
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
CB, October 12, 2004
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Maxwell Copelof was a government official and private arbitrator.
Copelof served as Code Authority director, National Recovery Administration? panel arbitrator, New York State Board of Mediation; commissioner of conciliation, Arbitration Division, U.S. Department of Labor? and as a panel member, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service.
Copelof's private arbitration activities included service as impartial chairman, New York Corset Manufacturers Association and the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union and as impartial chairman or permanent arbitrator for several firms and unions in the textile, ladies' clothing and paper manufacturing industries and as an arbitrator for numerous individual cases. Copelof was also the author of MANAGEMENT-UNION ARBITRATION (N.Y.: Harper and Brothers, 1948).
Scope and Contents
Contains transcripts, briefs, awards, and decisions relating to cases arbitrated by Maxwell Copelof.
Significant cases include Amalgamated Bank of New York vs. United Office and Professional Workers of America (UOPWA) on the issue of job assignment (1941); American Bank Note Company vs. International Printing Pressmen and Assistants' Union of North America and Paper Handlers and Straighteners Union on issues of managerial prerogatives and starting and quitting times (1947); American Cyanamid Company vs. United Mine Workers of America, District 50, on issues of rates of pay, job classification, layoffs, and arbitrability (1949); American Hardware Corp. vs. United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE) on issues of rates of pay, seniority, vacation pay, and retroactive pay (1946-1947); American Hide and Leather Company vs. International Fur and Leather Workers' Union on issues of standards of production and rates of pay (1945); American Locomotive Company vs. United Steelworkers of America (USWA) on issues of overtime, schedules of work, time and motion studies, rates of pay, vacations and vacation pay (1943-1947); American Table Manufacturing Company vs. United Furniture Workers of America (UFW) on issues of rates of pay, job classification, holidays, holiday pay, and vacation pay (1942-1944); and American Woolen Company vs. Textile Workers' Union of America (TWUA) on issues of schedules of work, rates of pay, and reinstatement following illness or physical disability (1942-1949).
Other cases include Amoskeag-Lawrence Mills, Inc. vs. TWUA on issues of standards of production, workload, rates of pay, managerial rights, arbitrability, discipline, discharge, layoff, and elimination of jobs (1945-1948); Arlington Mills vs. Federation of Woolen and Worsted Workers, AFL, on issues of standards of production, workload, rates of pay, equal pay for equal work, overtime, job classification, and bonus pay (1942-1946); Amory Worsted Mills vs. TWUA on issues of rates of pay, piecework vs. day work, vacations, vacation pay, and managerial prerogatives (1947-1948); Associated Shoe Industries,
Inc. vs. International Brotherhood of Firemen and Oilers on issues of rates of pay, holidays, and holiday pay (1946-1949); and Avon Sole Co, vs. Brotherhood of Shoe and Allied Craftsmen, Rubber Sole and Heel Local, on issues of classification of jobs, rates of pay, discipline and discharge (1944-1949).
Additional cases include Baldau Co. vs. United Packinghouse Workers of America (UPWA) on issues of rates of pay, discrimination, and recall (1949); Beggs & Cobb, Inc. vs. International Fur and Leather Workers' Union on the issue of rates of pay (n.d.); Beko Spinning Mill vs. TWUA on issues of union shop and schedules of work (1946); Bendix Corporation vs. United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW) on issues of job assignment, added duties, elimination of jobs, promotion, seniority, and tardiness (1945); Boston Sausage and Provision Co, vs. UPWA on issues of discharge, standards of production, work breaks, overtime pay, performance of bargaining unit work by foremen and supervisors, violation of plant rules, holiday pay, layoff, and seniority (1942-1950); and Branch River Wool Combing Co. vs. TWUA on issues of work stoppage, past practice, insubordination, absenteeism, back pay, elimination of jobs, leave of absence, reduction in workforce, job transfers, contract modification, rates of pay, reporting pay, and vacation pay.
Other cases include Celanese Corporation of America vs. UMW, District 50, on issues of working conditions and safety in shop (1947); Colonial Provision Co., Inc. vs. UPWA on issues of rates of pay and disciplinary discharge (1942-1949); Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers Association vs. Corset and Brassiere Workers Union on issues of strikes and slowdowns (1939); Cranston Print Works Co. vs. United Textile Workers of America on issues of rates of pay, union security, standards of production, workload, discrimination, and union activities (1946); Endicott-Johnson Company vs. various operating employees of E-J on issues of rates of pay (1943-1945); Endicott-Johnson vs. United Shoe Workers of America on the issue of rates of pay (1945); and Fitchburg Yarn Co. vs. TWUA on issues of vacancies, seniority, arbitrability, and assignment of jobs (1945-1949),
Other cases include Geisenheimer-Lewin, Inc. vs. Underwear and Negligee Workers Union on issues of rates of pay and discrimination (1938); General Cable Corp. vs. International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) on issues of transfers, seniority, vacations, rates of pay, and equal pay for equal work (1943-1946); Gimbel Bros. vs. General Warehousemen's Union on issues of rates of pay and contract modification (1941); Gimbel Bros. vs. Retail Clerks International Protective Association on issues of contract modification and rates of pay (1941); Gimbel Bros. vs. Stenographers, Bookkeepers, Typists, Accountants and Assistants Union of Pittsburgh on issues of contract modification and rates of pay (1941); Gimbels Thirty-Third St. and Saks Thirty-Fourth St. vs. Department Store Employees Union on the issue of reinstatement (1949); and Gold Seal Shoe Co. vs. United Shoe Workers of America on issues of rates of pay, discipline, discharge, strikes, slowdowns, composition of bargaining unit,
Additional cases include International Shoe Company vs. United Shoe Workers of America on issues of rates of pay, disciplinary discharge, daywork vs. piecework, layoffs, promotions, transfers, filling of job vacancies, incentive pay, reinstatement following physical disability, reinstatement following leave of absence, disciplinary layoff, retroactive pay after pay rate revision, relation of foremen to bargaining unit, job classification, and discrimination in rates of pay (1943-1948); Monsanto Chemical Corp. vs. UE on issues of vacation pay, job classification, working conditions, rates of pay, equal pay for equal work, disciplinary layoff, job assignment, and disciplinary action for insubordination (1945-1949); Murray Co. vs. UE on issues of job jurisdiction, disciplinary discharge, and disciplinary suspension (1943-1944); and Mutual Shoe Co. vs. Marlboro Shoe Workers Associates, Inc. on the issue of reinstatement following military service (1943).
Other cases include New York and Brooklyn Casket Company, Inc. vs. United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America on the issue of reinstatement following military service (1945); and Pittsburgh Plate Glass Co. (Libby-Owens-Ford Glass Co.) vs. Federation of Glass, Ceramic and Silica Sand Workers of America on issues of contracting out union work, managerial prerogatives, seniority, rates of pay, contract modification, insubordination, standards of production, incentive pay, crew size, arbitrability, disciplinary layoff, job transfers, union security, and job jurisdiction (1943-1946).
Other cases include Taber Instrument Corp. vs. UE on issues of discrimination and union representation (1947); Valley Motor Transit Co. vs. International Association Machinists (IAM) on the issue of interest arbitration (1944); Valley Motor Transit Co, vs. Amalgamated Association of Street, Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America on the issue of interest arbitration (1944); and West Virginia Pulp and Paper Co. vs. United Paperworkers of America on issues of rate revision, rates of pay, discrimination, job classification, introduction of new technology, creation of new jobs, promotion, retroactive pay, discharge for improper personal conduct, layoff, job assignment, change in location, functions of supervisors and foremen, and reduction in workforce (1948-1950). Also substantial numbers of additional routine arbitrations in the shoe, women's clothing industry, and local transit industries.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5221: Max Meyer Papers 5780/002: ILGWU David Dubinsky Correspondence
Arbitration, Industrial -- New York (State) -- Cases; Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Cases; Equal pay for equal work -- United States; Industrial arbitrators; Clothing workers; Textile workers; Absenteeism -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Aircraft industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Banks and banking -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Chemical industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Coffin industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Electric industries -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Furniture industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Glass manufacture -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Hosiery industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Leather industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Local transit -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Meat industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Metal-workers -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Paper industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Printing industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Retail trade -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Shoe industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Textile industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Women's clothing industry -- United States; Discrimination in employment -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Employees, Dismissal of -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Hours of labor -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Industrial engineering -- Locomotive building -- United States; Job descriptions -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Job security -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Labor discipline -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Labor productivity -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Layoffs -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Misconduct -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Open and closed shop -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Vacations, Employee -- Law and legislation -- United States; Position classification -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Seniority, Employee -- Law and legislation -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Shoe industry -- United States; Technological innovations -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Union security -- Law and legislation -- United States; Wages -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Wages -- Shoe industry -- United States; Wages -- Textile industry -- United States; Wages -- Women's clothing industry -- United States; Amalgamated Association of Street, Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America; Amalgamated Bank of New York; American Bank Note Company; American Cyanamid Company; American Hardware Corporation; American Hide and Leather Company; American Locomotive Company; American Table Manufacturing Company; American Woolen Company; Amory Worsted Mills, Inc.; Amoskeag-Lawrence Mills, Inc.; Arlington Mills; Associated Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers, Inc.; Associated Shoe Industries, Inc.; Avon Sole Company; Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America; Baldau Company; Beggs & Cobb, Inc.; Beko Spinning Mill; Bendix Corporation; Boston Sausage and Provision Company; Branch River Wool Combing Company; Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers of America; Brotherhood of Shoe and Allied Craftsmen; Brotherhood of Shoe and Allied Craftsmen. Rubber Sole and Heel Local; Celanese Corporation of America; Colonial Provision Company, Inc.; Corset and Brassiere Workers Union; Cranston Print Works Company; Endicott-Johnson Company; F.J. Murray Co.; Federal Labor union 21914; Federal Labor Union 22539; Federation of Glass, Ceramic and Silica Sand Workers of America; Federation of Woolen and Worsted Workers; Fitchburg Yarn Company, Inc.; Geisenheimer-Lewin, Inc.; General Cable Corporation; General Warehousemen's Union; Gimbel Brothers, Inc.; Gold Seal Shoe Company; Industrial Trades Union of America; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America; International Association of Machinists; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers; International Brotherhood of Firemen and Oilers; International Fur and Leather Workers Union of the United States and Canada; International Printing Pressmen and Assistants' Union of North America; International Shoe Company; International Union of Operating Engineers; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America; International Union, United Automobile Workers of America (A.F. of L.); Kent Shoe Corporation; Libby-Owens-Ford Glass Company; Marlboro Shoe Workers Associates, Inc.; Monsanto Chemical Corp; Mutual Shoe Company; New York and Brooklyn Casket Company; Paper Handlers and Straighteners Union; Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company; Playthings, Jewelry and Novelty Workers' International Union; Retail Clerks International Protective Association; Saks Department Store; Stenographers, Bookkeepers, Typists, Accountants and Assistants Union of Pittsburgh; Taber Instrument Corporation; Textile Workers Union of America; Transport Workers Union of America; Underwear and Negligee Workers Union; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America; United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America; United Furniture Workers of America; United Mine Workers of America. District 50; United Office and Professional Workers of America; United Packinghouse Workers of America; United Paperworkers of America; United Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Employees of America; United Shoe Workers of America; United Steelworkers of America; United Textile Workers of America; United Wire and Metal Workers Union; Valley Motor Transit Company; West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company; Wholesale and Warehouse Workers Union
3833937
- ABC Steel & Wire Co., New York City vs. United Wire & Metal Workers Union, CIO, Local 36, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  6/12/46 Issue: discipline - discharge.
- Airedale Worsted Co., Woonsocket, RI vs. Industrial Trades Union of America, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  11/15/45 Issue: rates of pay - piecework vs. day work.
- Airway Mfg. Corp., Newark, NJ vs. Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), Local 696., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  11/19/45 Issue: rates of pay - increases; vacation pay.
- Alabama Flour Mills (Division of Nebraska Consolidated Mills Co.) Decatur, AL vs. United Textile Workers of America, Local 191 (UTWA)., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  8/9/49 Issue: discipline - layoff.
- Alabama Flour Mills (Division of Nebraska Consolidated Mills Co.) Decatur, AL vs. United Textile Workers of America, Local 191 (UTWA), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  10/26/49 Issue: discipline - discharge
- Alco Mfg. Corp., Rockingham, N.C. vs. TWUA, L. 603, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  2/7/49 Issue: standards of production - workload.
- Aldrich Mfg. Co., Charlton City, MA vs. TWUA, L. 192., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  9/12/42. Issue: rates of pay - increases; vacations & vacation pay.
- Alea Mfg. Corp., Rockingham, N.C. vs. TWUA, South Central Joint Board. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Issue: standards of production - workload. No date, no decision
- Aleo Mfg. Co. vs. TWUA, Local 603. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Algy Shoes Inc., Everett, MA vs. United Shoe Workers of America, Local 1., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  3/15/44. Issue: rates of pay - adjustment.
- Algy Shoes Inc., Everett, MA vs. United Shoe Workers of America, Local 1., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  8/12/42. Issue: rates of pay - increases.
- Algy Shoes Inc., Everett, MA vs. United Shoe Workers of America, Local 1.., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  11/16/42. Issue: rates of pay - increases.
- Algy Shoes Inc., Everett, MA vs. United Shoe Workers of America, Local 1., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  10/30/43. Issue: reinstatement.
- Amalgamated Bank of New York vs. United Office and Professional Workers of America, Local 16 (UOPWA)., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  8/21/41. Issue: assignment of jobs - assignment of work outside unit.
- American Bank Note Co., New York, NY vs. International Printing Pressmen's & Assistants Union of N.A., Paper Handlers & Straighteners Union #1., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  11/3/47. Issue: management rights - starting and quitting time change.
- American Cyanamid Co., Warners Plant, Linden, NJ vs. United Mine Workers of America (UMW), District 50, Local 12426., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  9/1/49. Issue: rates of pay - classification of jobs.
- American Cyanamid Co., Warners Plant, Linden, NJ vs. United Mine Workers of America (UMW), District 50, Local 12426., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  11/22/49. Issue: arbitrability; layoff - remedy for improper layoff.
- American Hardware Corp. New Britain, CT vs. United Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers of America (UE), Local 232., 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  12/46, 1/11/47. Issue: rates of pay - retroactive pay; seniority - breaks in continuity; rates of pay - reduction; vacation pay - eligibility.
- American Hardware Corp. New Britain, CT vs. United Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers of America (UE), Local 232., 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  12/46, 2/11/47. and clarification dated 5/23/47. Issue: rates of pay - premium pay.
- American Hide & Leather Co., Lowell, MA vs. International Fur & Leather Workers' Union of the U.S. and Canada., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  7/17/45. Issue: standards of production - rates of pay.
- American Locomotive Co., Schenectady Works, Schenectady, NY vs. United Steelworkers of America (USW), Local 2054., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  9/14/43. Issue: overtime - schedules of work.
- American Locomotive Co., Dunkirk, NY vs. USW, Local 2286., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  12/24/43. Issue: time studies - new standards; rates of pay - downtime.
- American Locomotive Co., Schenectady, NY vs. USW., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  1/29/45. Issue: discipline - discharge; promotions.
- American Locomotive Co., Diesel Engine Div., Auburn, NY vs. USW, L.3482., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  2/19/47. Issues: rates of pay - increase; vacations & vacation pay.
- American Optical Co., Southbridge, MA vs. Kenneth Morrison, Employee., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  10/13/47. Issue: discipline - discharge.
- American Radiator & Standard Sanitary Corp., Bayonne, NJ vs. UE., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  8/19/46. Issue: classification of jobs - upgrading.
- American Table Mfg. Co., Everett, MA vs. United Furniture Workers of America (UFW), Local 1363., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  5/11/44. Issue: classification of jobs - rates of pay; holidays and holiday pay; vacation pay.
- American Table Mfg. Co., Everett, MA vs. United Furniture Workers of America (UFW) Local 136., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  4/18/42. Issue: rates of pay - increase
- American Table Mfg. Co., Everett, MA vs. United Furniture Workers of America (UFW), Local 136-B., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  2/4/43. Issue: rates of pay - increase.
- American Thread Co., Kerr Mills, Fall River, MA vs. TWUA, Local 445., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  9/22/43. Issue: Assignment of jobs - transfer of work.
- American Thread Co., Merrick Mills, Holyoke, MA vs. TWUA, Local 512., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  3/13/43. Issue: rates of pay - increase.
- American Thread Co., Merrick Mills, Holyoke, MA vs. TWUA, Local 512., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  10/30/43. Issue: standards of production - workload.
- American Thread Co., Merrick Mills, Holyoke, MA vs. TWUA, Local 512., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  6/10/44. Issue: rates of pay - incentive pay.
- American Thread Co., Merrick Mills, Holyoke, MA vs. TWUA, Local 512., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  11/28/44. Issue: rates of pay.
- American Welding Co., Carbondale, PA vs. USW, Local 2135., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  8/17/44. Issue: classification of jobs - rate of pay.
- American-West African Line, Inc., New York vs. Commercial Telegraphers Union, Radio Officers Union., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  1/18/44. Issue: overtime.
- American Woolen Co., Andover, MA vs. UTWA, Local 38., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  6/30/49. Issue: reinstatement - following illness or physical disability.
- American Woolen Co. (Wood Worsted ill), Lawrence, MA vs. UTWA, Local 227., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  5/7/42. Issue: schedules of work - shift scheduling.
- American Woolen Co. (Wood Worsted ill), Lawrence, MA vs. UTWA, Local 227., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  4/12/43. Issue: shift scheduling - rotation of shifts.
- American Woolen Co., Andover, MA, Vassalboro, ME, Dover-Foxcraft, ME vs. UTWA, Dept. of Woolen & Worsted Workers., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  11/29/46. Issue: rates of pay. Issue: reinstatement - following illness or physical disability.
- Amos-rice Coal Co., vs. IBTCS & HA, AFL, Coal & Dump Truck Drivers & Handlers Union, Local 540., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  7/28/43. Issue: rates of pay.
- Amoskeag-Lawrence Mills, Inc., Manchester, NH vs. TWUA, Local 560., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  3/20/48. Issue: standards of production - workload.
- Amoskeag-Lawrence Mills, Inc., Manchester, NH vs. TWUA, Local 560., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  4/29/48. Issue: rates of pay
- Amoskeag-Lawrence Mills, Inc., Manchester, NH vs. TWUA, Local 560., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  5/27/48. Issue: rates of pay.
- Amoskeag-Lawrence Mills, Inc., Manchester, NH vs. TWUA, Local 560., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  2/6/50. Issue: rates of pay - incentive pay.
- Amoskeag-Lawrence Mills, Inc., Manchester, NH vs. TWUA, Local 560., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  10/31/45. Issue: standards of production - workload.
- Amoskeag Mills, Inc., Manchester, NH vs. TWUA, Local 864., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  11/29/47. Issue: arbitrability; management rights - operation of the business.
- Amoskeag Mills, Inc., Manchester, NH vs. TWUA, Local 864., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  4/29/48. Issue: arbitrability; discipline - discharge.
- Amoskeag Mills, Inc., Manchester, NH vs. TWUA, Local 864., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  11/26/48. Issue: layoff - elimination of job.
- Amoskeag Mills, Inc., Manchester, NH vs. TWUA, Local 864., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  9/4/48. Issue: discipline - discharge.